<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles in journals on Arthur Van Camp</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles in journals on Arthur Van Camp</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Inferring from an imprecise Plackett–Luce model: Application to label ranking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/fss2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/fss2024/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The Plackett–Luce model is a popular parametric probabilistic model to define distributions between rankings of objects, modelling for instance observed preferences of users or ranked performances of algorithms. Since such observations may be scarce (users may provide partial preferences, or not all algorithms are run for a given experiment), it may be useful to consider the case where the parameters of the Plackett–Luce model are imprecisely known. In this paper, we first introduce the imprecise Plackett–Luce model, induced by a set of parameters (for instance, parameters with a high relative likelihood).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Independent natural extension for choice functions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/ijar2023a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/ijar2023a/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We introduce an independence notion for choice functions, which we call &amp;rsquo;epistemic independence&amp;rsquo; following the work by De Cooman et al. (2011) for lower previsions, and study it in a multivariate setting. This work is a continuation of earlier work of one of the authors, and our results build on the characterization of choice functions in terms of sets of binary preferences recently established by De Bock and De Cooman (2018).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exposing some points of interest about non-exposed points of desirability</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/ijar2022a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/ijar2022a/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We study the representation of sets of desirable gambles by sets of probability mass functions. Sets of desirable gambles are a very general uncertainty model, that may be non-Archimedean, and therefore not representable by a set of probability mass functions. Recently, Cozman (2018) has shown that imposing the additional requirement of even convexity on sets of desirable gambles guarantees that they are representable by a set of probability mass functions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modelling epistemic irrelevance with choice functions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/ijar2020a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/ijar2020a/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We consider coherent choice functions under the recent axiomatisation proposed by De Bock and de Cooman that guarantees a representation in terms of binary preferences, and we discuss how to define conditioning in this framework. In a multivariate context, we propose a notion of marginalisation, and its inverse operation called weak (cylindrical) extension. We combine this with our definition of conditioning to define a notion of irrelevance, and we obtain the irrelevant natural extension in this framework: the least informative choice function that satisfies a given irrelevance assessment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal control of a linear system subject to partially specified input noise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/ijrnc2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/ijrnc2019/</guid>
      <description>Abstract One of the most basic problems in control theory is that of controlling a discrete-time linear system subject to uncertain noise with the objective of minimizing the expectation of a quadratic cost. If one assumes the noise to be white, then solving this problem is relatively straightforward. However, white noise is arguably unrealistic: noise is not necessarily independent, and one does not always precisely know its expectation. We first recall the optimal control policy without assuming independence and show that, in this case, computing the optimal control inputs becomes infeasible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exchangeable choice functions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/ijar2018b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/ijar2018b/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We investigate how to model exchangeability with choice functions. Exchangeability is a structural assessment on a sequence of uncertain variables. We show how such assessments constitute a special kind of indifference assessment, and how this idea leads to a counterpart of de Finetti’s Representation Theorem, both in a finite and a countable context.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coherent choice functions, desirability and indifference</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/fss2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/fss2017/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We investigate how to model indifference with choice functions. We take the coherence axioms for choice functions proposed by Seidenfeld, Schervisch and Kadane as a source of inspiration, but modify them to strengthen the connection with desirability. We discuss the properties of choice functions that are coherent under our modified set of axioms and the connection with desirability. Once this is in place, we present an axiomatisation of indifference in terms of desirability.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lexicographic choice functions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/ijar2018a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/ijar2018a/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We investigate a generalisation of the coherent choice functions considered by Seidenfeld et al. (2010), by sticking to the convexity axiom but imposing no Archimedeanity condition. We define our choice functions on vector spaces of options, which allows us to incorporate as special cases both Seidenfeld et al.’s (2010) choice functions on horse lotteries and also pairwise choice—which is equivalent to sets of desirable gambles (Quaeghebeur, 2014)—, and to investigate their connections.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing Dirichlet priors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/tas2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/tas2016/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The selection of prior distributions is a problem that has been heavily discussed since Bayes and Price published their paper in 1763. Conjugate priors became popular, largely because of their mathematical convenience. In this study, we justify the use of the conjugate combination of a Dirich- let prior and a multinomial likelihood by imposing a fundamental principle that we call partition invariance, alongside other requirements that are well known in the literature.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Representation theorems for partially exchangeable random variables</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/fss2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/fss2016/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We provide representation theorems for both ﬁnite and countable sequences of ﬁnite-valued random variables that are considered to be partially exchangeable. In their most general form, our results are presented in terms of sets of desirable gambles, a very general framework for modelling uncertainty. Its key advantages are that it allows for imprecision, is more expressive than almost every other imprecise-probabilistic framework and makes conditioning on events with (lower) probability zero non-problematic.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
